

ANNA SEMJONOVA

JUNIOR QA ENGINEER

CONTACT INFORMATION

Address: Kungu iela 79-8, Liepaja, Latvia. LV-3401

Phone: +371 29123128

E-mail:

anna.semjonova.en845@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/annasemjonova-27668b17b

Portfolio:

https://annaen845.github.io/Petproject/

HARD SKILLS

- Theoretical knowledge of software testing methodologies and processes
- Functional testing, GUI testing, localization testing
- Bug Reporting, Check-List, Test case
- JIRA, uTest bug tracking system
- Postman API
- Charles Proxy, Fiddler
- Android Studio
- Command line, Git, GitHub, ADB
- JMeter
- Basic knowledge SQL
- Basic knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript

PERSONAL PROFILE

I completed The Software Testing Basics Course successfully and also received a letter of recommendation from the QA Academy Director. I have experience in finance and business. I would like to have a career in the software field, beginning as a QA Engineer.

ADDITIONAL TRANING

QA Engineer Course by Vadim Ksendzov: June 2021 - present. Learned practical skills in Postman API, Charles Proxy, Fiddler, Android Studio, ADB, JMeter, SQL

The Complete Web Developer in 2021: Zero to Mastery, instructor Andrei Neagoie, Udemy platform, 2021 - present. Learned practical skills in HTML, CSS, basic JavaScript, Bootstrap, DOM Manipulation, Command Line, Git, Sublime Text3.

The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp, instructor Dr. Angela Yu, Udemy platform, 2021 - present. Learned practical skills in HTML, CSS, basic JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, DOM Manipulation, Command Line, Git, Atom.

The uTest Academy, Applause, 2019. Participated in Web and Mobile Application testing projects. Performed functional and GUI testing. Wrote bug reports and submitted them into the uTest bug tracking system. Submitted Test Cases and Test Reviews. Collected browser logs, Android device logs, and Web debugging proxy logs. Used tools: ShareX, AZ Screen Recorder, Minimal ADB and Fastboot, Charles Proxy, DevTools.

Software Testing Basics QA Academy international education center, Testing Planet LTD, 2018. Learned of theory, such as basics of testing, and participated in 5 Web Application testing projects. Performed functional and GUI testing. Wrote bug reports and submitted them to Jira.

I Software QA Testing for beginners video lessons, Portnov Computer School, 2018.

EDUCATION

Professional Bachelor's degree in Business administration and qualification Companies and Institutions Manager, Turiba University, 2007 - 2011.

Junior College degree in Finance and Lending, Riga Technical University, 1996 - 2000.

ANNA SEMJONOVA

JUNIOR QA ENGINEER

SOFT SKILLS

- Good Interpersonal skills
- Problem solving skills
- Excellent time management skills
- Decision-making skills

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Latvian Native/Bilingual
- Russian Native/Bilingual
- English Intermediate
- Spanish Elementary
- Lithuanian Elementary

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance software tester, Applause, 12.2020 - Present

Performed Web and mobile application manual testing - functional testing, GUI testing, localization testing. Wrote quality bug reports with supporting screenshots, log files, videos and submitted them to the uTest bug tracking system.

Self-employed, Riga, 2014 - 2020

Built a successful small beauty business, offered lessons for students Hands-On Training&Products, and how to become an entrepreneur or a freelancer in the field of beauty.

Maintained a working knowledge of products, equipment, services, alternative delivery channels. Analyzed business operations, costs, revenues.

Independent Contractor, Preferiti LTD, Riga, 2006 - 2018

Assisted clients in drawing up business plans and managed projects for small and medium-sized enterprises for the attraction of European Union structural funds.

Consulted on registration, closure, and changes for the board members of companies.

Coordinated documentation of security system installation projects.

Bookkeeper & Accountant, Artels AG LTD, Riga, 2003 - 2011

Prepared financial statements, income statements, balance sheets, and cash flow statements.

Processed invoices, daily transactions, expenses, monitored daily cash flow.

Updated and maintained accounting database.

Bank Teller & Customer Service Clerk, Swedbank Corporation, Riga, 2001 -2002

Worked as a front-line customer service professional.

Promoted and advised on the bank's products and services to customers.

Balanced cash in cash drawer at end of each shift. Confirmed customer identity, maintained and updated account information.

Bank Customer Service Clerk, Norvik Banka Corporation, Riga, 2000 -2001

Processed customer transactions, maintained financial data

Answered visitor questions, directed customers to bank personnel.